（人類出現之前）
（在浩瀚的宇宙中）
（有無數文明）
（索馬里斯星球）
-我去告訴她 -不 不 我...
-I'm just gonna go tell her. -No. No, I...
我要親自告訴她
I wanna tell her myself.
她知道你離開后是什么情況
She knows what it's like for you to be away.
你帶領過探索任務
You've led explorations before.
好幾個月
Not for this long.
-最多六星期 -她是個堅強的孩子
-Six weeks at most. -She's a resilient kid.
-但這不是補給運輸 -她會沒事的
-She'll be fine. -But this isn't supply transport.
或者跳轉到瑟林并返回 為期兩年
Or a jump to Cyllene and back. It's a two-year run.
我知道 我知道多久
I know. I know how long.
去吧
-Just go. -It's hard.
很難 我會去 我只是想要如何開口
I'll go. I'm just thinking about what to say.
說他們給你三倍薪水 所以我們才能負擔她的醫療
Say they're tripling your salary, which is how we can afford to treat her.
令她康復 你沒事吧？
-To cure her. -You okay?
我沒事
I'm fine.
是兩年...
It's two years...
我不會在這里
I won't be here.
我知道 但是當你回來 她會在
I know, but when you get back, she will.
爸
Dad!
我做不到
I can't do it.
你沒事吧？
You okay?
沒事
Yeah, yeah.
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
爸 我要你教我如何吹
Dad, I just want you to help me with this.
這樣 別太用力吹
Here. Don't blow so hard.
慢慢 輕輕的 我想我的拇指太小了
-Just easy. A little gentle. -I think my thumbs are too small.
你的拇指很好 你只是太用力吹
Your thumbs are perfect. You're just blowing too hard.
這樣 看我
Here, watch me. Watch me.
為何你總能做好每件事？ 你令它看起來很容易
Why are you so good at everything? You make it look so easy.
這很容易 你只是需要懂得技巧
It is easy. You just have to know how to do it.
別吹進去 往下吹
-Don't blow in, blow down. -Okay.
你這樣做
This is you.
只需要輕輕吹
It isn't. Just blow a little gently.
好
Okay.
別氣餒 再試
Don't get frustrated. Try again.
沒事 我知道
It's okay. I know.
你知道什么？ 我知道你要離開
-What do you know? -I know that you're leaving.
我知道這是因為我
And I know it's 'cause of me.
不是因為你 這是為了你
No, it's not because of you, it's for you.
這次要離開多久？
So how long will you be gone this time?
佐伊克探索機3703
Zoic Exploratory Charter 3703.
檢測到異常流星活動
Unexpected meteor activity detected.
計算風險評估
Running risk assessment.
檢查乘客生命體征
Checking passenger vitals.
冷凍：正常
Cryostasis, normal.
警告：異常流星活動
Warning. Unexpected meteor activity.
需要手動操作
Manual override required.
緊急著陸
Emergency landing.
冷凍箱：受損
Cryochamber compromised.
緊急轉發 這是運輸機3703
Emergency transpondence, this is Charter 3703!
我們的飛船被擊中 它要墜落了！
Our ship has been hit and is going down!
你害怕嗎？
Are you scared?
軌跡：偏離航線
Trajectory off-course.
位置：不明
Location unknown.
軌跡：偏離航線
Trajectory off-course.
位置：不明
Location unknown.
軌跡：偏離航線
Trajectory off-course.
位置：不明
Location unknown.
軌跡：偏離航線
Trajectory off-course.
冷凍故障
Cryogenic failure.
讀取緊急著陸數據庫
Accessing emergency landing database.
飛行路徑軌跡受到干擾
Flight path trajectory interrupted.
目前位置：不明
Current location unknown.
這是佐伊克運輸機3703
This is the Zoic Charter 3703.
如果有人收到 我是遠程探索任務的唯一幸存者
If anyone receives this, I'm the only survivor of a long-range exploratory mission.
我的船被一個未記錄的小行星帶擊中
My ship was struck by an undocumented asteroid belt.
我相信這些碎片來自 一個更大的隕石的一個流星團
I believe the debris to be a small cluster from a much larger asteroid system.
但是我不確定
But I can't be sure.
我們迫降在一個未知的星球上
We've crash-landed on an uncharted celestial body.
我的船斷裂成兩半
My ship has been severed in half.
確定九個逃生艙被毀還有兩個失蹤了
Confirmed nine escape pods have been destroyed and two are missing.
空氣是可呼吸的
The atmosphere is breathable.
所有的乘客都死了
All passengers are dead.
派救援
Send help.
已刪除
Deleted.
這是運輸機3703 長程探索任務
This is Charter 3703, long-range exploratory mission.
隕石碎片擊中我的船
Asteroid debris field hit my ship.
所有乘客都死了 沒必要搶救
All passengers are dead. No reason for recovery.
訊息已發送
Message sent.
三
Three...
二
two...
一
one.
讀取庫存
Accessing archive.
還記得我們前陣子去的海灘嗎？
Remember when we went to the beach a while ago?
你還記得它有多冷嗎？
And do you remember how, like--? Just cold it was?
在外面是什么感覺？
What does it feel like out there?
（6千5百萬年前）
（一名探訪者墜落在）
（地球）
你在哪里？
Where are you?
掃描逃生船位置
Scanning for escape vessel location.
位置：不明
Location unknown.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
尋獲佐伊克船體
Section of the Zoic located.
逃生船的距離 15公里
Distance to escape vessel, 15 kilometers.
嘿！
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
停！
Stop!
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
你的名字？
Your name?
好 讓我們查看你是誰
Okay. Let's find out who you are.
好 乘客號碼... 35
Passenger number 35.
你的名字一定是小柯
Your name must be Koa.
沒事
It's okay.
來 我們看看這燙傷
Here, let's look at this burn.
小柯 我叫米爾斯 我是這艘船的飛行員
Koa, my name is Mills. I was the pilot of the ship.
在我們墜落之前 我正在送你們回家
I was transporting you home before we crashed.
而你在冷凍中...
And you've been in cryostasis for...
很久了
a long time.
導航系統故障了 我不知道我們在哪里 這里是未知的
The navigation system is gone. I don't know where we are. It's uncharted.
有一艘逃生船
There is an escape vessel.
但是在高山上
But it's high above in the mountains.
那是我們唯一離開這星球的機會
That's our only chance to get you off the planet.
外面有一些異獸...
There's something alien out there...
那很危險
that is dangerous.
你明白我嗎 小柯？ “小柯” 對嗎？
You understand me, Koa? I mean, it's Koa?
你說什么？
What'd you say?
那是什么語言？
What language is that?
我不能...
Well, I can't...
我不能翻譯 我不明白
I can't translate. I don't understand.
不 我不明白 我不能翻譯它
No, I don't understand. I can't translate it.
我的翻譯機壞了 像這艘船的其他東西一樣
My translator's broken. Like everything else on this damn ship.
那是什么語言 庫利語嗎？
What is that, Kuu'ri?
帕利斯卡語？
Pris'ka?
山
Mountain.
我們必須爬上山頂
We-- We must climb all the way to the top of the mountain.
另一半的船體在那里
That's where the other half of our ship is.
船
Ship.
“山”？你明白“山”嗎？
Mountain? Do you understand mountain?
逃生船 這里有一艘逃生船
Escape vessel. Here's an escape vessel.
那里是我們...
That's where we...
這里
Over here.
這是你離開的辦法
That's how you leave.
這是你回家的辦法 家
-That's how you get home. -Home.
什么？
What?
-家 -是的
-Home. -Yes.
家
Home.
是什么 你的父母嗎？
What is it, your parents?
家人？
Family?
家人
Family.
在山頂上
On the top of the mountain.
這就是我要告訴你的 他們在山頂上
That's what I'm trying to tell you. On top of the mountain.
-家人 -是的
-Family. -Yeah.
他們在這里
They're here.
運輸機3703 奧納家的女兒還活著
Charter 3703. The daughter of the Ona family is alive.
一個小孩 可能9歲 健康良好
A child, maybe 9 years old and in good health.
她叫小柯 來自上方地區 所以我們無法溝通
Her name is Koa, from the upper territories, so we are unable to communicate.
她的父母是乘客
Her parents were passengers.
雙亡了
Both deceased.
我要帶她去遙遠的逃生船
I'm taking her to an escape vessel I've located some distance away.
發送求救
Send help.
發送求救信號
Sending distress signal.
是的 這是一艘船 跟你工作時開的一樣
Yeah, that's a ship. Just like the one you're driving for work.
出發！
Blast off!
我做的 你能相信嗎？
I made it. Can you believe it?
學校很有趣
School's been pretty fun.
我考得好成績 一切很順利
I've been getting good grades, and everything's been going well.
我很想念你 因為我愛你
I miss seeing you 'cause I love you.
你好！ 我們有一些好消息
Hello. We have gotten some amazing news.
這令我很開心因為你已經在一半的行程了
It's made me very happy 'cause you have made it halfway.
這是你的成功一半的慶祝
Here is your halfway celebration.
我為你感到自豪
I'm very proud on you--
為你成功一半而自豪
Proud of you. For making it halfway.
我想媽已經告訴你了 有一些...
I think Mom told you, but there's just a little
我有一些小問題 所以...
minor problem going on with me, so...
但是這里真的很有趣 我認識了一些好人
But it's actually really fun here and I've met some nice people.
他們令我想起你 因為你是我最好的朋友 還有...
And they remind me of you because you are my greatest friend, and...
請快回來
Hurry back, please.
加速
Speed it up.
我現在真的很恨你
I really hate you right now.
你根本不在乎我
You don't even care about me.
我要你知道我...
Just want you to know I...
我愛你
I love you.
我很累 爸
I'm so tired, Dad.
我累了
I'm tired.
我嘗試...
I'm try--
好了 我們走吧
All right, let's go.
走吧
Let's go.
跟著我
Stay with me.
我們必須安靜地爬上山
We need to be quiet and move to the mountain.
安靜
Quiet.
和移動
And move.
移動
Move.
繼續走
Keep moving.
逃生船的距離 12公里
Distance to escape vessel, 12 kilometers.
來 握我的手
Here, take my hand.
沒事吧？
You okay?
好 我們走
All right, let's go.
不要吃
Don't eat.
從你的口直下去你的胃
In your mouth down to your stomach.
糟了
Shit.
嘿！
Hey!
不
No, no, no.
不 嘿！
No. Hey! Hey!
小柯
Koa.
別管它！
Leave it. Leave it!
糟了
Shit.
你必須聽我說
You have to listen to me.
你會害死自己
You're gonna get yourself killed.
我累了！
I'm tired!
我很累！
I'm just tired!
我很累
I'm just tired.
不 我...
No. I'm...
我說我很累
I'm saying I'm just tired.
我很累
I'm just tired.
要喝水嗎？
Want some water?
水 沒事
Water. It's okay.
填滿它
Well, fill it up.
用水填滿它
Fill it with water.
-水 -水
-Water. -Water.
來 去平坦的那邊
Here, go to the other side where it's flat.
水
Water.
這是一朵花
It's a flower.
花 是的
-Flower. -Yeah.
不 我不要
No, that's okay.
花
Flower.
訊號干擾
Signal disruption.
目的地消失
Destination lost.
掃描中
Scanning.
“別吃”
"Don't eat."
不要！
No, no! No, no!
拿你的腿來
Give me your foot.
用力踩
Push. Push.
跑
Run.
沒事
It's okay.
你受傷了嗎？
Are you hurt?
你沒事吧？
You all right?
小柯 我們必須走了
Koa, we gotta go.
走
Move.
好吧
All right.
我們等
We'll wait.
走嗎？
Move?
走
Move.
我們現在安全了 你可以睡覺
We're safe now. You can sleep.
睡
Sleep.
家
Home.
家在外面那里
Home is out there.
檢測到異常
Irregularity detected.
掃描以識別
Scanning to identify.
目前無法識別異常
Unable to identify irregularity at this time.
可能會有更多的流星雨
Could be more of the asteroid shower.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
為何拿著這個？
Why'd you take this?
好 去睡吧
Go to sleep.
然后我把它貼在...
And then I'll stick it...
這里...
here...
現在看起來有點...
So now it kind of looks like it's--
鐵線令它看起來很不錯
The wire makes it look pretty nice.
但是我還要添加一點紅
But I'm just gonna add this touch of red also.
她很愛你
She loved you so much.
她沒受苦 她只是...
She didn't suffer, she just...
她只是慢慢逝去
She just slipped away.
小柯
Koa. Koa.
Koa
小柯！
Koa!
你沒事吧？
You okay?
掃描替代路徑
Scanning for alternate path.
檢測到定向氣流
Directional air current detected.
家人
Family.
是的 我們就是要去那里
Yeah, that's where we're headed.
去見你的家人
To see your family.
不 還不夠
No, it's not enough.
山
Mountain.
走？走！ 小柯
Move? Move! Koa.
我不能移動一座山
I can't move a mountain.
我不能 它被塞住了
Look, I can't. It's blocked.
我不能再前進
I can't go any further.
我不能穿過這塊石頭
I can't get past this rock.
就是這樣
That's it.
山！
Mountain!
小柯 山
Koa. Koa. Mountain.
走 小柯 山 走！
Move. Koa, mountain, move!
走！
Move!
那山上沒有人
There's no one on that mountain.
我騙你 對不起 他們死了
I lied to you, and I'm sorry. They're gone.
你不明白我
And you don't understand me.
不 對不起 我不能再前進了！ 我沒有任何工具了！
No, I'm sorry. I can't go any further. I don't have any more tools!
你沒事吧？
You all right?
以防萬一
Just in case.
不要動
Stay.
不！
No!
No. No!
天啊！
God!
小柯 不！
Koa, no!
小柯！
Koa!
啟動近距離掃描
Proximity scan initiated.
放開我！
Get off me!
掃描異常
Scanning irregularity.
檢測到災難性流星
Catastrophic asteroid detected.
評估鄰近風險
Assessing proximity risk.
撞擊迫在眉睫
Collision imminent.
小柯！
Koa.
Koa!
小柯！
謝謝
Thank you.
撞擊我們的流星嗎？
The asteroid that hit our ship?
更新軌跡
Updating trajectory.
那里 流星撞擊：12小時內
-There. -Asteroid impact: 12 hours.
它只是更大的一小部分 看到這個嗎？
It was just a small part of a much bigger one. See this?
這個嗎？
This?
它來著這里
It's coming here.
小柯
Koa.
好
Okay.
把它綁在一些穩固的東西上
Tie it around something safe.
這里
Right here.
小柯！
Koa!
Ko--
做得好
Good job.
求救信號已收到
Distress signal received.
攔截點坐標：012016
Interception point coordinates: 012016.
救援飛船來著 飛船來著
The rescue vessel's coming. The vessel's coming.
生命維持系統正常運作
Life support is working.
導航系統良好
Navigational system's good.
如果這個沒問題 就是...
If this is working, which it...
我想可能...
I think may--
小柯
Koa.
家人
Family.
家人！
Family!
對不起
I'm sorry.
家人！
Family! Family!
不
No. No.
小柯
Koa.
這是我的女兒
This is my daughter.
你明白嗎？
You understand?
我最后一次見她時 她氣我
The last time I saw her, she was mad at me.
因為我的工作令我離開她
Because my job took me away from her.
當我離開后 她病得很重
And when I was gone, she got very sick.
當她死的時候 我沒有在她身邊
She died and I wasn't there for her.
我要送你回家
I need to get you home.
小柯？
Koa?
對不起
I'm sorry.
準備好了嗎？
Ready?
好 檢查發射順序
Okay, checking launch sequence.
-那是發射按鈕 -發射
-That's the launch button. -Launch.
米爾斯
Mills.
發射順序失敗
Launch sequence failure.
飛船定位無法操作
Vessel orientation inoperable.
糟了
Shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
花了我一些時間
It just took me some time.
我終于做對了
I was able to get it right.
我做到了
I got it.
聲音怎樣？
How's it sound?
我愛你
I love you.
飛船方向已恢復
Vessel orientation restored.
修復周期啟動
Repair cycle initiated.
發射船！
Launch the ship!
天啊！
God!
撞擊迫在眉睫
Impact imminent.
攔截點坐標：012016
Interception point coordinates: 012016.